Matt Roth

Fullstack Web Developer

mattroth.dev@gmail.com | 1 (818) 331- 0729 | mattroth.dev

OBJECTIVE

- Enthusiastic developer seeking to fill a Web Developer position that will allow my skills to grow alongside the success of the company. Optimistic, motivated to continuously improve, and well-suited to working on a team.
- 1 year of professional experience in working with modern web development technologies, Including Django, React/Typescript, Git, and Azure DevOps.

SUMMARY

Intrinsically motivated developer specializing in JavaScript and JavaScript based frameworks. Competent in git version control systems, Python, and has some experience in designing database schema. Primarily works in Linux operating system environments, but is comfortable in Windows and OSX environments as well. Possesses a B.A.in Biological Anthropology, 1 year of professional experience, and a genuine enjoyment of learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SASS, Python

Frameworks: Bootstrap, Tachyons, Styled Components, React, Django, Gatsby

Databases: Sqlite3, Graphql

OS: Linux, Windows, OSX

• Version Control: Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Chrome Dev Tools, Firefox Dev Tools, Postman, Netlify

EDUCATION

University of California Santa Barbara, Goleta, CA — B.A Biological Anthropology

AUGUST 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

WORK HISTORY

Acclaim Academic Institute, La Palma, CA — Fullstack Web Developer

October 2019 - January 2021

Fulfilled the role of full stack developer in producing new features and improving performance for an online learning and scheduling platform. Gained experience in React/Typescript front end development, as well as Django back end development and database management. Projects included: an interactive avatar builder for student accounts, a vocabulary database and search tool, and improvements to a shared interactive, real-time IDE used for teaching Python.

Ilinx Studios, Hollywood, CA — *Fullstack Web Developer*

June 2019 - October 2019

Worked on a 5 person dev team. Gained experience working with Python, the Flask framework, and gained knowledge regarding game design and product development cycles. Configured a JavaScript web app to utilize real-time stock information, and implemented a user sign-up/sign-in framework to prepare the company's gaming platform, Whale, for its beta launch.